# **GUANGNENG HU**

PhD, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (+86) 14715483429 \$\diamonup\$ njuhgn@gmail.com \$\diamonup\$ (WeChat) zydxhgn

#### STATEMENT HIGHLIGHTING

My research belongs to artificial intelligence (AI) in general, focusing on transfer learning and natural language processing with applications in recommender system enabling it to be generalists, capable of continuously learning, and adapting to cold-start scenarios in open environments.

- I was awarded as prestigious Hong Kong PhD Fellowship (HKPF) issued by Research Grants Council, Hong Kong. (Acceptance rate 0.3% worldwide)
- I have published eight first-author papers at top-tier conferences and journals, including WWW, EMNLP, IJCAI, CIKM, NAACL, and ACM TKDD, achieving more than 250 citations (Google Scholar https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=\_mpy5bEAAAAJ&hl=en). My paper published in CIKM 2018 is ranking No. 6 (No. 2) in worldwide (China) among "Most Influential CIKM Papers".
- I was invited as AAAI 2021 Workflow Co-chair. I served as PC member for top-notch conferences (ACL/EMNLP/NAACL, ICML/NeurIPS/ICLR, AAAI/IJCAI, CSCW/ICWSM, WWW) and journals (IEEE TPAMI) more than 30 times.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Ph.D., Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

2016 - 2021

—Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

Thesis: Deep and Adversarial Knowledge Transfer in Recommendation

Advisors: Prof. Qiang Yang & Lei Chen (Co-supervisor)

Hong Kong PhD Fellowship Scheme

# M.S., Nanjing University

2013 - 2016

—Dept. of Computer Science & Technology

Natural Language Processing Group

Advisors: Prof. Xinyu Dai & Jiajun Chen (Group director)

National Scholarship, Ministry of Education

#### B.A., Nanjing University

2009 - 2013

—Dept. of Computer Science & Technology

GPA: 4.33/5, Rank: 17/175

Recommended Postgraduate Exempt from Exam

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

Hong Kong PhD Fellowship Scheme, Hong Kong (200/6000)	2016-2020
AAAI-21 Workflow Chair Honorarium, AAAI	2020-2021
"Most Influential CIKM Papers" Ranking #6, CIKM 2018 (6/862)	2018
Excellent Master Thesis Mention, Nanjing University (3/157)	2016
Excellent Graduate Student, Nanjing University (13/157)	2016
National Scholarship, Ministry of Education	2015
National Scholarship for Encouragement, Ministry of Education (7/175)	2011, 2012

## **EXPERIENCES**

# Workflow Co-chair: AAAI 2021. Hong Kong (Virtual)

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

· Implement program chairs' logic. Chairs: Prof. Mausam & Kevin Leyton-Brown

#### Research Intern: Memect, Inc. Beijing

Jan 2016 - Feb 2016

· Financial data analysis with natural language processing. Manager: Dr. Jie Bao

## Research Intern: Tencent, Inc. Shenzhen

July 2015 - Oct 2015

· Tencent Ads, Text analysis with embeddings. Manager: Dr. Rick Jin

## **PUBLICATION**

**Book Chapter** 

1. Weike Pan & Guangneng Hu. Chapter: Transfer Learning in Recommender Systems, In Transfer Learning by Qiang Yang, Yu Zhang, Wenyuan Dai & Sinno Pan, Cambridge University Press, 2020.

Peer-Reviewed Journal

1. [TKDD 2018]. **Guang-Neng Hu**, Xin-Yu Dai, Feng-Yu Qiu, Rui Xia, Tao Li, Shu-Jian Huang & Jia-Jun Chen. *Collaborative Filtering with Topic and Social Latent Factors Incorporating Implicit Feedback*, ACM Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data (ACM TKDD), 12(2): Article No. 23, 2018. **CCF-B** 

Peer-Reviewed Conference [main conf long]

- 8. [WWW 2021]. Bairan Fu\*, Wenming Zhang\*, Guangneng Hu, Xinyu Dai, Shujian Huang & Jiajun Chen. Dual Side Deep Context-aware Modulation for Social Recommendation, The Web Conference (TheWebConf) 2021. Virtual. (Acceptance Rate: 20.6%) CCF-A, Long
  \*Informally co-advised master students
- 7. [EACL 2021]. Guangneng Hu & Qiang Yang. TrNews: Heterogeneous User-Interest Transfer Learning for News Recommendation, European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL) 2021. Virtual. Long
- 6. [EMNLP 2020]. **Guangneng Hu** & Qiang Yang. *PrivNet: Safeguarding Private Attributes in Transfer Learning for Recommendation*, Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) Findings, 2020. Virtual. (Acceptance Rate: 22.4%) **CCF-B**
- 5. [NAACL 2019]. **Guangneng Hu**. Personalized Neural Embeddings for Collaborative Filtering with Text, North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL), 2019. Minneapolis, USA. (Acceptance Rate: 21.3%) **CCF-C**
- 4. [WWW 2019]. **Guangneng Hu**, Yu Zhang & Qiang Yang. Transfer Meets Hybrid: A Synthetic Approach for Cross-Domain Collaborative Filtering with Text, The Web Conference (TheWeb-Conf), 2019. San Francisco, USA. (Acceptance Rate: 18.0%) **CCF-A**
- 3. [CIKM 2018]. Guangneng Hu, Yu Zhang & Qiang Yang. CoNet: Collaborative Cross Networks for Cross-Domain Recommendation, Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2018. Turin, Italy. (Acceptance Rate: 17.1%) CCF-B, Long Ranking No. 6, "Most Influential CIKM Papers", CIKM 2018

- 2. [PAKDD 2017]. Guang-Neng Hu & Xin-Yu Dai. Integrating Reviews into Personalized Ranking for Cold Start Recommendation, Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2017, Jeju, South Korea. (Acceptance Rate: 28.2%) CCF-C, Long
- 1. [IJCAI 2015]. Guang-Neng Hu, Xin-Yu Dai, Yunya Song, Shujian Huang & Jiajun Chen. A Synthetic Approach for Recommendation: Combining Ratings, Social Relations, and Reviews, International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2015, Buenos Aires, Argentina. (Acceptance Rate: 28.7%) CCF-A, Long

The First CCF-A Paper by Student in NJU-NLP Lab

# Peer-Reviewed Workshop

- 3. [NeurIPS 2018 WS]. Guangneng Hu & Yu Zhang. Personalized Neural Embeddings for Collaborative Filtering with Unstructured Text, NeurIPS 2018 Workshop on Relational Representation Learning.
- 2. [KDD 2018 WS]. Guangneng Hu, Yu Zhang & Qiang Yang. MTNet: A Neural Approach for Cross-Domain Recommendation with Unstructured Text, KDD 2018 Deep Learning Day.
- 1. [ICML 2018 WS]. Guangneng Hu, Yu Zhang & Qiang Yang. CoNet: Collaborative Cross Networks for Cross-Domain Recommendation, ICML 2018 Workshop on Learning with limited labels.

## **GRANTS & SPONSORSHIP**

HKPFS Strengthened Funding Support, Research Grants Council of Hong Kong	2021
HKPFS Conference Allowance, Research Grants Council of Hong Kong	2018,2019
Research Travel Grant, Hong Kong University of Science & Technology	2017,2018,2019
Student Travel Grant, NAACL 2019 & SIGIR 2018	2018,2019
Research Travel Grant, Nanjing University	2015

#### CONTRIBUTING PROJECTS

NSFC (61472183/61333014) and 863 Program (2015AA015406)	IJCAI'15, PAKDD'17, TKDD'18
NSFC (61673202) and 973 Program (2014CB340304)	CIKM'18, WWW'19, NAACL'19
NSFC (61976114/61936012)	WWW'21
National Key R&D Program (2018AAA0101100)	EACL'21
Hong Kong CERG Projects (16211214/16209715/16244616)	EMNLP'20

#### PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Workflow Co-Chair:

• 2021: AAAI-21, 2021, AAAI.

Session Chair:

• 2015: IJCAI-15 main track, 2015, Buenos Aires, Argentina.

Student Volunteer:

• 2019: NAACL 2019, 2019, Minneapolis, USA.

Journal Reviewer:

• 2021: IEEE TPAMI

PC Member:

• 2022: ICLR

- 2021: EACL, NAACL, ICWSM, CSCW, CogSci, ICML, IJCAI, ACL, EMNLP, NeurIPS
- 2020: AAAI, ICML, ACL, EMNLP
- 2019: ICWSM, MobileHCI, ACL, CSCW, ISWC, EMNLP

Emergency Reviewer & Subreviewer:

- 2021: ACL, ICML
- 2020: WWW, IJCAI, NeurIPS

#### INVITED TALKS AND ORAL PRESENTATION

On News Recommender Systems and Transfer Learning, EACL, Virtual, 2021.

On Content-based Recommender Systems, NAACL, Minneapolis (USA), 2019.

On Recommender Systems and Transfer Learning, WeChat, Guangzhou, 2019.

On Deep Transfer Learning, KDD-Workshop, London (UK), 2018.

On Deep Transfer Learning, CIKM, Turin (Italy), 2018.

On Content-based Recommender Systems, PAKDD, Jeju (Korea), 2017.

On Recommender Systems and Data Fusing, Memect, Inc, Beijing, 2016.

On Hybrid Recommender Systems, IJCAI, Buenos Aires (Argentina), 2015.

On Recommender Systems, Tsinghua University, 2015.

On Recommender Systems, Chinese Information Processing Society of China, Nanjing, 2015.

### **ADVISING & TEACHING**

Informally Co-Advising:

• Master students: Bairan Fu & Wenming Zhang, Nanjing University, 2020 - 2021

Teaching Assistant:

- Honors Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structures (C++), UG core, HKUST, 2018
- Machine Learning, PG Core, HKUST, 2018
- Compilers, UG Core, Nanjing University, 2015
- Numerical Computation, UG course, Nanjing University, 2014

## SOCIAL SERVICE & MEDIA

Social Service:

- Librarian Assistant, Nanjing University, 2013-2015
- Computer Lab Assistant, Nanjing University, 2009-2013
- Counsellor Assistant, Nanjing University, 2011-2012

## Media:

- Transfer learning tips, WeChat Official Accounts, Reading 18K, 2020
- Wikipedia Contributor, Over 700 edits, since 2014

- $\bullet\,$  Tips for fighting spam emails, Junior Science Magazine, 2014
- Weibo We Media, AI related 4K posts, 14K+ followers, Since 2013